A Guide to the Deferred surveys, from the Virginia Land Office, 1931-1953
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Deferred surveys, from the Virginia Land Office, 1931-1953
The Library of Virginia
LOI 47
.35 cu. ft. (1 box)
Virginia. Land Office
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession LOI 47 transferred by the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1948.
Historical Information
The act which established the previous Land Office passed the General Assembly on 22 June 1779. The register was the head of the Office and was appointed by joint ballot of both houses of the legislature. The office of the Superintendent of Weights and Measures was abolished by an act of 7 February 1867, and his duties were transferred to the register of the Land Office. The records of the Land Office which were in the custody of the Secretary of the Commonwealth were transferred to the State Library, and, by Act of Assembly on 5 March 1952, the duties of the regsiter of the Land Office were transferred from the Secretary of the Commonwealth to the State Librarian.
Scope and Content
Contains the preliminary plats and certficates which were not carried into grants. Also includes relevant correspondence, much of it with the state librarian, Randolph W. Church, as well as receipts.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Virginia. Land Office
Subjects:
Surveying -- Virginia.
Genre and Form Terms:
Land surveys -- Virginia; State government records -- Virginia
Contents List
- Deferred Surveys, 1931-1953., Extent: 1 box (.35 cu. ft.). (Box 1)
  Alphabetical
  - Bishop, S. W., 1937. (Folder 1)
  - Davis, Cornelia B., 1937. (Folder 2)
  - Haxall, Barton A., 1946. (Folder 3)
  - Hoover, William D., and Frank Stetson, 1931-1932. (Folder 4)
    Warrant No. 32499
  - Adkins, Morell T., 1951. (Folder 5)
    Warrant No. 33689
  - Alvis, Mason, 1950-1952. (Folder 6)
    Warrant No. 33674
  - Baldwin, J. W. W., 1948-1950. (Folder 7)
    Warrants No. 33649, 33667
  - Baldwin, J. W. W., 1953. (Folder 8)
  - Baldwin, J.W.W., and C. B. Belcher, 1951. (Folder 9)
    Warrant No. 33680
  - Baylor, J. H., 1950. (Folder 10)
    Warrant No. 33663
  - Belcher, C. B., 1950. (Folder 11)
    Warrant No. 33610
  - Burgess, Fred, 1951. (Folder 12)
    Warrant No. 33686
  - Carter, Charles Carroll, 1951-1953. (Folder 13)
    Warrants No. 33676, 333677
  - Crymes, T. N., 1950. (Folder 14)
  - Dearing, Dovie, 1952. (Folder 33694)
    Warrant No. 33694
  - DeSance, Douglas, 1949. (Folder 16)
    Warrant No. 33653
  - Dillon, Ray A., 1951-1953. (Folder 17)
    Warrant No. 33682
  - Donati, L. N., 1949. (Folder 18)
    Warrant No. 33656
  - Dunn, Joseph E., 1949. (Folder 19)
    Warrant No. 33651
  - Earles, Willie B., Mrs., 1950. (Folder 20)
    Warrant No. 33675
  - Forrest, Beamon T., 1948. (Folder 21)
    Warrant No. 33647
  - Hennaman, L. W., 1950. (Folder 22)
    Warrant No. 33666
  - Hogg, William Edward, 1951. (Folder 23)
    Warrant No. 33692
  - Mapp, Ivan, 1947. (Folder 24)
    Warrant No. 33640
  - Matney, Charles, 1951. (Folder 25)
    Warrant No. 33679
  - Minter, C. S., 1949-1951. (Folder 26)
    Warrant No. 33659
  - Montague, Winston, 1951. (Folder 27)
    Warrant No. 33693
  - Myers, A. R., 1948. (Folder 28)
    Warrant No. 33644
  - Orange, Manley R., James Rennie, and W. J. Ready, 1950. (Folder 29)
    Warrant No. 33673
  - Robertson, John A., 1950. (Folder 30)
    Warrant No. 33664
  - Russell, Frederick P., 1940-1949. (Folder 31)
    Warrant No. 32578
  - Taylor, R. Vernon, 1948. (Folder 32)
    Warrants No. 33648, 33662
  - Webb, Bernard L., 1948. (Folder 33)
    Warrant No. 33652
  - William, A. D., 1951. (Folder 34)
    Warrant No. 33691